<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts.atom"/>
  <title>Weave Got It Canada - Hair Facts</title>
  <updated>2018-01-18T14:21:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Weave Got It Canada</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-hair-extensions-bundle</id>
    <published>2018-01-18T14:21:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-04T16:12:02-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-hair-extensions-bundle"/>
    <title>What is a Bundle?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Why would I use a bundle?</h2>
<p>If you're looking to add length and volume to your hair, bundles are a great option. The lengths you choose will determine how the cut of your hair will look. Some people like to choose different lengths for dramatic layers. Others choose the same length for slight layers. No matter what you choose, you can cut,<span> </span>colour<span> </span>and style this hair however you want.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<div class="video-container"><iframe width="640px" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EdqHkZkDM7Y?rel=0&amp;start=5" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">What is a Bundle?</h1>
<p style="text-align: left;">Think about a bundle the same way you think of a pack of hair extensions. Each bundle is 100 g of <span>virgin </span>remy<span>100% human</span> hair, no matter the length. The part of the bundle that is sewn is referred to as the weft. You will need more bundles for longer styles. </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Bundles can be installed with the sew-in method, glue in, micro-ring or a number of other techniques. You could also convert your bundles to clip-ins after time.  </p>
<h2>Are bundles for me?</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you've never used hair extensions, you could start with clip-ins as an easy way to test them out. Bundles can be installed by a hair stylist or you could put them in yourself.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">They come in 1 really long weft, rolled into the shape of a bundle.  Some choose to cut the bundle into manageable pieces while others prefer sewing the bundle into a braided base, by folding it back and forth.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Take a look at our guide to see how many bundles you might need. </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extensions-bundles-wefts" target="_blank" title="Shop-now-human-hair-extension-bundles" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_9.jpg?v=1520193239" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; float: none; width: 100%;"></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">How long will it last? </h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">We source only the highest quality hair to ensure our bundles last a long time. From a year to two years and beyond, our beauties use and reuse their hair extensions. By treating them like you own and washing, conditioning and trimming regularly, your hair will be around for many different styles.</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-base-wig</id>
    <published>2017-12-28T19:17:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-05T20:51:27-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-base-wig"/>
    <title>What is a Base Wig?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Why would I use Base Wig?</h2>
<p>Our Base Wigs are a hit! For the everyday woman or the full-time glam artist, our base wigs give you the full versatile look you've always wanted. </p>
<p>With lace front and full lace options, you choose how you'd like to style yours. Style it, <strong>wash it</strong>, cut it and repeat, over and over again. You can even colour it or at length with bundles or clip-ins later. Achieve any style you want with this base. </p>
<p>  <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/amaQtHpZVGs" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">What is a Base Wig?</h2>
<p>It's a beautifully constructed machine sewn wig with your choice of custom options like clips, an adjustable strap &amp; frontal strap. Perfect for everyday or special occasion, consider the Base Wig the perfect go-to!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">What's the difference between a lace front &amp; full lace?</h2>
<p>The lace is the part of the wig that looks like natural growth. Hairs are hand-tied to the lace, to give the appearance of natural growth.</p>
<p>On a <strong>lace front wig</strong>, this would be a 13x4 inch section across the front of the wig. It gives you the flexibility to part it anywhere along the hairline. The rest of the wig is filled in with regular hair extensions wefts. There's also a small piece of lace in the back if for a natural neckline when putting it up in a ponytail.</p>
<p>With a <strong>full lace wig</strong>, the entire wig is constructed with lace. This gives you complete freedom in choosing your hairstyles as you can part it all the way down the middle or french braid it if you really wanted to. The wig customization options are the same for a full lace. </p>
<p><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/base-wigs-lace-front-wigs-full-lace-wigs" target="_blank" title="/base-wigs-lace-front-wigs-full-lace-wigs" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_12.jpg?v=1520196149" alt="human-hair-full-lace-wigs-and-lace-front-wigs" width="598" height="313" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">How long will it last? </h2>
<p>The great thing about a wig is that you can take it off when you feel like it ;). I'm still rockin' a wig I made 3 years ago.  With proper care, you can expect 1-2 years from one of our Base Wig collection. Be gentle with the pressure you put on your lace and your wig will be a girlfriend of yours for a long time to come.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-360-lace-frontal</id>
    <published>2017-12-28T19:17:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-05T20:38:21-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-360-lace-frontal"/>
    <title>What is a 360 Lace Frontal?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Why would I use a 360 closure?</h2>
<p>Our newest type of closure is the 360 Lace Frontal. Perfect for making a wig or finishing your protective style with no natural hair left out. With hairline coverage for all the way around your hairline, you'll be able to part it anywhere around and even rock a ponytail! If you want ultimate versatility in your weave, 360 is the way to go. </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lZcalMw6pv0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">What is a 360 Lace Frontal?</h2>
<p>It's a 4 x 22 inch lace hairpiece that covers the natural hairline entirely. It has adjustable straps, making it easy to get the right fit. E<span>ach hair is hand-tied to our</span> lightweight French lace. W<span>ith skin </span>colour<span> underneath, h</span>air appears to be growing from the scalp. </p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Is a 360 Lace frontal for me?</h2>
<p>If you've tried a lace closure or frontal before, is the next level. As with any lace hairpiece, there are techniques for making it look as natural as possible. With the perfect install and proper maintenance, 360 lace frontal takes, the #1 spot for the most versatile weave. </p>
<p>First time? Feel free to reach out to us. We're happy to answer any questions you have.  </p>
<p><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extensions-360-lace-frontal" target="_blank" title="shop-now-360-lace-closure" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_11.jpg?v=1520195159" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; float: none; width: 100%;"></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">How long will it last? </h2>
<p>Our 360 lace frontal is specially handcrafted to fit your crown. You can customize the hairline of your lace frontal to mimic your natural hairline. With proper care, you can expect 6 months to 1 year from one of our lace frontals with proper care. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-frontal</id>
    <published>2017-12-28T19:17:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-12T07:52:57-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-frontal"/>
    <title>What is a Lace Frontal?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Why would I use a Lace Frontal?</h2>
<p>One of the most popular ways to finish your protective style is a lace frontal. Perfect for style with no natural hair left out. With hairline coverage from ear to ear, you'll be able to part it anywhere and have complete versatility. Lace frontals are for finishing your weave hairstyle or when creating a wig.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SjxSRt_VQOM" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">What is a Lace Frontal?</h1>
<p>It's a 13 x 4 inch lace hairpiece that covers the front hairline. This is perfect looking for protective styles with no hair left out. When installed correctly, it gives the illusion of hair growing from your scalp.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Is a lace frontal for me?</h2>
<p>If you've never tried a lace frontal, imagine laying a thin piece of fabric along your hairline. It's comfortable and comes with baby hairs along the lace hairline. For less coverage, you could try a lace closure. For full hairline coverage, the 360 Lace Frontal is a great option. </p>
<p>Feel free to reach out to us if this your first time using a silk closure. We're happy to answer any questions you have.  </p>
<p><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extensions-lace-frontals" target="_blank" title="shop-now-human-hair-extensions-lace-frontals" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_13.jpg?v=1520197432" alt="shop-now-lace-frontal" style="display: block; float: none; width: 100%; margin: 30px auto 30px auto;"></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">How long will it last? </h2>
<p>Our hand tied lace frontal is a special piece for us. We take pride in giving you the most natural look possible. With proper care, you can expect 6 months to 1 year from one of our lace frontals with proper care. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-silk-closure</id>
    <published>2017-12-28T19:17:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-05T19:42:01-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-silk-closure"/>
    <title>What is a Silk Closure?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Once you've used a lace closure, it's natural to want to try a silk closure. It's used to finish your protective style with or without hair left out. The difference is that you can't see through the closure like you can with lace. With the proper installation, silk is hard to detect.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-silk-closure">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: left;">Why would I use a silk closure?</h2>
<p>Once you've used a lace closure, it's natural to want to try a silk closure. It's used to finish your protective style with or without hair left out. The difference is that you can't see through the closure like you can with lace. With the proper installation, silk is hard to detect.</p>
<p>Silk closure pieces are a made with a fine piece of coloured silk. They look very natural even really close up. It's often used to finish wigs as well.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;">What is a Silk Closure?</h1>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6t4cSCHUpiY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> It's a 4x4 inch silk piece with a lace base for strength. When secured to the crown section, your weave becomes a lot more flexible. The hair's volume against the silk gives the natural look of scalp when parted. </p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Is a silk closure for me?</h2>
<p>A silk closure offers natural flexibility. At a higher price point than a lace closure, some people never try a silk and that's ok, while others swear by it. It's really about your personal preference. Another option for more hairline coverage is a Lace Frontal or for full hairline coverage, the 360 Lace Frontal.</p>
<p>Feel free to reach out to us if this your first time using a silk closure. We're happy to answer any questions you have.  </p>
<p><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extensions-silk-closures" target="_blank" title="shop-now-silk-closure" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_10.jpg?v=1520193952" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; float: none; width: 100%;"></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">How long will it last? </h2>
<p>The silk is sewn to our French lace which is soft on your skin. Each hair is tied into the silk with invisible knots. With consistent use, it will last from 6 months to 1 year with proper care. Some say longer.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-closure</id>
    <published>2017-12-28T19:17:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-11T22:34:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-closure"/>
    <title>What is a Lace Closure?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>It's a 4x4 inch lace piece that is secured to the crown section of your head to finish a weave. The hair's natural volume against the lace gives the look of scalp when parted. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-closure">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Why would I use a closure?</h2>
<p>Going for the natural look is the biggest reason to choose a Lace Closure. It's a more natural finish for your full protective style (no natural hair left out) or a style with some natural hair left out. </p>
<p>Lace pieces are not new. Over the years they've evolved to be more common use for the everyday weave wearer. </p>
<p style="text-align: center;">  <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6t4cSCHUpiY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">What is a Lace Closure?</h1>
<p>It's a 4x4 inch lace piece that is secured to the crown section of your head to finish a weave. The hair's natural volume against the lace gives the look of scalp when parted. </p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Is a lace closure for me?</h2>
<p>If you're interested in having a natural look that's flexible and allows you to change up your style, a lace closure is a great option. For more coverage, you also have the option of a Lace Frontal or 360 Frontal, which cover more of your hairline. </p>
<p>Feel free to reach out to us if it will be your first time with lace at your hairline. We're happy to answer any questions you have.  </p>
<p><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extension-lace-closures" title="shop-now-human-hair-lace-closures" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_8.jpg?v=1520188955" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; float: none; width: 100%;">&gt;</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">How long will it last? </h2>
<p>Our French lace is soft on your skin. It very durable and lightweight. Each hair is hand tied to the lace with care and precision. With consistent use, it will last from 6 months to 1 year with proper care.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/whats-the-difference-between-package-hair-and-bundles</id>
    <published>2017-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-11T19:12:45-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/whats-the-difference-between-package-hair-and-bundles"/>
    <title>What&apos;s the difference between package hair &amp; bundles?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Put simply, most of the time, the difference between bundle hair and packaged hair for the beauty supply store is the quality. When buying bundles, you are generally looking for 100% virgin </span>remy<span> hair, great quality that lasts a long time.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/whats-the-difference-between-package-hair-and-bundles">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template.png?v=1520255538" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; float: none; width: 100%;"></p>
<p>Put simply, most of the time, the difference between bundle hair and packaged hair for the beauty supply store is the quality. When buying bundles, you are generally looking for 100% virgin remy hair, great quality that lasts a long time.</p>
<p><span><span>This is not to say that you can't get quality hair at a hair store, you can. This will likely be the hair behind the counter. </span></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>For those who don't go there often, this can be very overwhelming. There are tons of brands, but just know that quality hair will last you a long time.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>The Construction</span></h3>
<p><span>Many times with packaged hair, the hairs on the weft come from many donors with many different types of hair and not much care is taken to ensure the hairs are the same length or lay in the same direction. When the hairs are not the same length or placed in the direction of growth (remy) it leads to matting, shedding and tangling.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extensions-bundles-wefts" title="weavegotit.ca hair extension bundles wigs and closures shop now"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Copy_of_Newsletter_Review_Template_1.png?v=1520809755" alt="hair extensions bundles shop now" style="display: block; float: none; width: 100%; margin: 10px auto 10px auto;"></a></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Our hair extension bundles are 100% virgin (never chemically treated) human hair. We set quality standards to ensure each bundle is perfectly full and soft. Hair comes in many textures, densities, and porosities and we feel it's important to have hair that looks and feels like your own.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/whats-the-difference-between-a-partial-weave-a-full-weave</id>
    <published>2017-03-12T00:25:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-12T07:52:10-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/whats-the-difference-between-a-partial-weave-a-full-weave"/>
    <title>What&apos;s the Difference Between a Partial Weave &amp; a Full Weave?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Samantha Renée</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<div class="rte post-content">
<div>When choosing your protective style, you may want to start by leaving some of your natural hair out, to master the technique of blending your hair extensions. If you'd rather cover all of your own hair, you can finish your weave and leave none of your hair out.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_3.png?v=1520828485" style="display: block; float: none; width: 100%; margin: 30px auto 30px auto;"></h3>
<h3>Partial Weave</h3>
<div>A partial weave style will allow you the flexibility of parting your own hair and using it as a bang if you leave out a good amount. Or, you can leave a small amount just to cover over the tracks/weft of your hair extensions. You can complete this style using only <a href="/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-hair-extensions-bundle">hair extension bundles</a>.</div>
<div></div>
<h3>Full Weave</h3>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>A full head of weave means that none of your natural hair will be left out. There are a few ways to complete this style, some techniques using only wefts and others with closure pieces. The closure options include <a href="/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-closure">lace closure</a>, <a href="/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-silk-closure">silk closure</a>, <a href="/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-lace-frontal">lace frontal</a> &amp; <a href="https://shereigns.ca/blogs/hair-facts/what-is-a-360-lace-frontal">360 lace frontal</a>.</div>
<div> </div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Check out <a href="https://weavegotit.ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">weavegotit.ca</a> lace frontals below!</div>
<div></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://weavegotit.ca/collections/human-hair-extensions-lace-frontals"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1980/8985/files/Newsletter_Sign_Up_Template_13.jpg?v=1520197432" style="display: block; float: none; width: 100%; margin: 30px auto 30px auto;"></a></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
